[
{
      "question":"Who among the following succeeded Pushyamitra Shunga?",
      "optionA":"Agnimitra",
      "optionB":"Sujyestha",
      "optionC":"Vajramitra",
      "optionD":"Devbhuti",
      "correctAns":"Agnimitra"
   },
   {
      "question":"Consider the following observations about the 'Sulbasutras' discussed in context with the ancient Indian history and heritage:The formulae in the Sulbasutras enabled the accurate construction of altars needed for sacrificesApart from Bodhayana, Lopamudra is also credited for some SulbasutrasThe mathematics in the Baudhayan’s Sulbasutras was algebraicWhich among the above observations is / are correct?",
      "optionA":"Only 1 is correct",
      "optionB":"Only 1 & 2 are correct",
      "optionC":"Only 2 & 3 are correct",
      "optionD":"1, 2 & 3 are correct",
      "correctAns":"Only 1 is correct"
   },
   {
      "question":"Consider the following statements:Both Mitakshara and Dayabhaga are ancient Indian legal textsBoth Jimutvahana and Vijnaneshwara were prominent Jurists of ancient IndiaWhich among the above is / are correct statements?",
      "optionA":"Only 1",
      "optionB":"Only 2",
      "optionC":"Both 1 & 2",
      "optionD":"Neither 1 nor 2",
      "correctAns":"Both 1 & 2"
   },
   {
      "question":"At which among the following places, Asoka has erected pillars surmounted with four lions?SarnathSanchiVaishaliLauriya-NandangarthSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1",
      "optionB":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionC":"Only 1, 2 & 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2, 3 & 4",
      "correctAns":"Only 1 & 2"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following statements about the Virupaksha Temple is / are correct?This temple is largest of monuments built by the Chalukyas of BadamiIt is known as the earliest example of a pillar based structure in temple architectureSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1",
      "optionB":"Only 2",
      "optionC":"Both 1 & 2",
      "optionD":"Neither 1 nor 2",
      "correctAns":"Both 1 & 2"
   },
   {
      "question":"Consider the following pairs of Sanskrit plays with their authors:Nagananda – HarshaRatnavali – KalidasPriyadarsika – SudrakaWhich of the above is/are correct?",
      "optionA":"1 & 2 Only",
      "optionB":"1 Only",
      "optionC":"2 & 3 Only",
      "optionD":"1, 2 & 3",
      "correctAns":"1 Only"
   },
   {
      "question":"With reference to the political conditions of India in around 4th century BC, which among the following statements is / are correct?There was no paramount power in Northern IndiaThere were no republican statesThere were not more than 16 independent statesSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1",
      "optionB":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionC":"Only 1 & 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2 & 3",
      "correctAns":"Only 1"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who among the following were the first native Indian rulers to issue their own coins?",
      "optionA":"Mauryas",
      "optionB":"Saatavahanas",
      "optionC":"Pallavas",
      "optionD":"Cholas",
      "correctAns":"Saatavahanas"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following terms with respect to Chola administration denote some kind of taxes?IdaivariAlugalsarakkuAngadipattamUppa-yamSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"1 2 3",
      "optionB":"2 3 4",
      "optionC":"1 3 4",
      "optionD":"1 2 3 4",
      "correctAns":"1 2 3 4"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following was the 23rd trithankar?",
      "optionA":"Abinandan Nath",
      "optionB":"Suvidhinatha",
      "optionC":"Arishtnemi",
      "optionD":"Parshavanath",
      "correctAns":"Parshavanath"
   }
]